<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Week 8: Strengthening Foundational AWS Knowledge and Expanding Cloud Optimization Skills :: AWS Intership Report</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_8/index.html</link>
    <description>Objectives: Reinforce foundational cloud concepts to prepare for deeper optimization work. Review cost management, security best practices, and performance tuning across major AWS services. Improve understanding of content delivery and edge optimization using AWS global infrastructure. Strengthen hands-on skills through structured practice and lab-style exercises. Tasks Completed: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Studied core prerequisites for cloud optimization: compute efficiency, storage tiering, and network design. - Reviewed concepts around global AWS infrastructure, edge locations, and how they impact latency and performance. 27/10/2025 27/10/2025 AWS Docs, Internet, mentor guidance Tue - Completed structured hands-on practice sessions focused on IAM, VPC networking, and S3 access control patterns. - Reinforced knowledge through scenario-based exercises involving cost-optimized architectures and workload placement. 28/10/2025 28/10/2025 AWS Labs, Internal docs Wed - Reviewed content delivery and caching concepts: CloudFront, caching layers, TTL optimization, and request routing. - Studied how distribution edge caching reduces origin load and enhances application performance. 29/10/2025 29/10/2025 AWS Edge Services Documentation Thu - Strengthened understanding of application security fundamentals: AWS WAF, mitigating common web threats, rate limiting, and bot protection strategies. - Applied these concepts in theoretical scenarios to improve overall architectural security posture. 30/10/2025 30/10/2025 AWS Security Docs, Internet Fri - Conducted a comprehensive review of learned topics: optimization strategies, caching, IAM hardening, network segmentation, and monitoring best practices. - Documented updated understanding into the Report Site for long-term reference. 31/10/2025 31/10/2025 Internet, mentor-provided materials Results: Built a stronger foundation in AWS optimization techniques across compute, storage, networking, and security. Gained deeper insight into edge delivery systems, caching layers, and how CloudFront improves performance and reduces cost. Improved understanding of AWS WAF and common methods for mitigating modern web threats. Reinforced core AWS service knowledge through practical review and structured lab-style exercises.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>