<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/index.html</link><description>Avatar Information Name: Lê Vương Định Phone Number: 0905215314 Email: ledinh539@gmail.com Education: FPT University Student Code: SE192671 Major: Information System Organization: AWS Việt Nam Position and Duration: Cloud Engineer Intern (09/2025 – 12/2025) Table of Contents Worklog Proposal Translated Blogs Events Participated Workshop Self-evaluation Sharing and Feedback</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Worklog</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/index.html</guid><description>Week 1: Introduction to AWS and Basic AWS Services Week 2: Exploring AWS Compute and Storage Services. Getting familiar with HUGO and related development tools Week 3: Setting up the report site with Hugo, exploring AWS security and database services Week 4: Security and Identity Management on AWS. Integrating CloudWatch and Cost Explorer into the project Week 5: Strengthening AWS Database Knowledge and Enhancing the Internship Report Site Week 6: Enhancing Multilingual Report Site and Exploring Basic DevOps Practices on AWS Week 7: Backend System Optimization and Expanding AWS Cost Monitoring Features Week 8: Strengthening Foundational AWS Knowledge and Expanding Cloud Optimization Skills Week 9: Deepening Cloud Optimization Skills and Exploring Web Application Performance &amp; Security Week 10: Exploring AWS AI/ML Foundations and Modern Generative AI Architectures Week 11: Edge Computing, Content Delivery Optimization, and Web Application Security on AWS Week 12: Strengthening AWS Security Architecture and Mastering Cloud Protection Best Practices</description></item><item><title>2. Proposal</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/2-proposal/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/2-proposal/index.html</guid><description>AWS Cloud Health Dashboard Download Official Project Plan (Docx) 1. Executive Summary AWS Cloud Health Dashboard is a production-grade, multi-tenant SaaS platform with automated DevSecOps implementation that enables businesses to monitor and optimize AWS infrastructure for multiple clients from a single centralized system.
Key Highlights: Production-Grade Architecture: Application Load Balancer with SSL/TLS termination, Elastic IP, health checks, and zero-downtime deployment capability DevSecOps Pipeline: Automated CI/CD with security scanning and blue-green deployment strategy Multi-tenant Architecture: Designed to support 10-50+ AWS client accounts (demo tested with 3-5 clients) High Availability: ALB with health checks, automatic failover capability, and 99.99% SLA Platform cost: $39-49/month (Year 1) with production-grade infrastructure Per-client cost: ~$0.59/month (scalable and predictable) Security-first design: AWS Secrets Manager + KMS encryption + ACM certificates Automated deployment: CodePipeline + CodeBuild with zero-downtime deployment 5 DynamoDB tables: Optimized data model with client isolation Redis caching: Potential 60-80% database read cost reduction Email notification system: AWS SES integration for critical alerts Elastic IP: FREE static IP for production stability Technology Stack: FastAPI (Python) + React + DynamoDB + Redis + ALB + Elastic IP + ACM + AWS Secrets Manager + KMS + CloudWatch + CloudTrail + CodePipeline + CodeBuild + EC2 t3.micro 2. Problem Statement Current Challenges: Businesses managing AWS infrastructure for multiple clients face:</description></item><item><title>3. Translated Blogs</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/3-blogs/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/3-blogs/index.html</guid><description>This section will list and introduce the blogs that I have translated.
Blog 1 - Implementing DevSecOps Ecosystem for Amazon Connect at NatWest. NatWest implemented Amazon Connect with a full DevSecOps ecosystem to power a large-scale, multi-team contact center. Instead of multiple instances, they ran a single shared Connect instance but separated environments across AWS accounts for dev, test, pre-prod, prod, and DR — improving control, security, and stability. Infrastructure was managed through modular Terraform, letting teams deploy independently while enforcing consistent naming, tagging, and security standards. For faster delivery, they built export-import CI/CD pipelines for Amazon Lex bots and QuickSight dashboards instead of writing everything as IaC. Security was multi-layered, combining preventive guardrails (modules, SCPs, static scanning) and detective controls (Config, Inspector, CloudWatch, Security Hub). They also developed utilities to export contact flows as Terraform, manage Contact Lens rules, and generate performance insights. The result: faster development, more reliable releases, stronger security, and a standardized way to operate Amazon Connect across the organization.</description></item><item><title>4. Events Attended</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/index.html</guid><description>During my internship, I participated in six AWS events — each one a memorable experience filled with new knowledge, hands-on learning, valuable insights, along with fun moments and community interaction.
Event 1 Event Name: AWS Cloud Day Vietnam 2025 &amp; GenAI Track
Time: 09:00 AM, September 18, 2025
Location: Level 26, Bitexco Financial Tower, 02 Hai Trieu Street, Saigon, Ho Chi Minh City
Role: Attendee
Event 2 Event Name: AWS Cloud Mastery Series #1 : AI/ML/GenAI on AWS
Time: 8:30 AM – 12:00 PM, November 15, 2025
Location: Level 26, Bitexco Financial Tower, 02 Hai Trieu Street, Saigon, Ho Chi Minh City
Role: Attendee</description></item><item><title>5. Workshop</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/index.html</guid><description>This is our group Workshop. Please review the below contents. Content Overview Prerequisites Create VPC &amp; Subnets Create Internet Gateway Create NAT Gateway Configure Route Tables Launch EC2 Instances Connectivity Tests Cleanup</description></item><item><title>6. Self-Evaluation</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/6-evaluation/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/6-evaluation/index.html</guid><description>During my internship at AWS Vietnam (September – December 2025), I had the opportunity to explore cloud computing in depth while building and documenting a practical learning project. I approached each task sincerely, researching carefully, understanding concepts before applying them, and prioritizing correctness over rushing.
Across the 12 weeks, I steadily expanded my abilities in AWS services, backend development, cloud optimization, DevOps, and security engineering. The internship helped me form a structured technical mindset and improved my confidence in working with real cloud infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>7. Sharing and Feedback</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/7-feedback/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/7-feedback/index.html</guid><description>Personal Feedback – AWS First Cloud Journey (FCJ) During my time in AWS Vietnam under the First Cloud Journey (FCJ) program, I experienced a learning environment that challenged me, accelerated my growth, and pushed me beyond the typical student-level knowledge.
FCJ rewards those who are self-driven. I believe it is an exceptional program, but not universally easy. It benefits students who come with curiosity, resilience, and the willingness to learn through action rather than instruction. People like me, who enjoy exploring deeply and independently, will grow extremely fast here.</description></item></channel></rss>