<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event 4 :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/event_4/index.html</link><description>EVENT REPORT: AWS Edge Services Workshop Date: Wednesday, November 19, 2025
Time: 8:30 AM – 5:00 PM
Location: AWS Vietnam Office, Bitexco Financial Tower, District 1, Ho Chi Minh City
Objective: Strengthen knowledge of global content delivery via CloudFront, enhance web application security with AWS WAF, and apply real implementation through interactive hands-on sessions.
AGENDA SUMMARY Time Topic Speaker(s) Key Focus 08:00 – 08:30 Registration &amp; Networking — Check-in and networking with AWS architects. 08:30 – 09:30 From Edge to Origin: CloudFront as Your Foundation Nguyễn Gia Hưng — Head of Solutions Architect CDN architecture, Edge locations, global content distribution optimization. 09:30 – 10:45 Attack Surface Defense: AWS WAF &amp; Application Protection Julian Ju — Senior Edge Services SA WAF rule sets, OWASP Top 10 mitigation, bot prevention. 10:45 – 12:00 Lunch &amp; Networking — Expanded discussions &amp; networking. 13:00 – 14:30 Hands-On: Optimize Internet Web Application Hưng, Julian, Kevin Lim CloudFront configuration, real-world performance tuning. 14:45 – 16:15 Hands-On: Secure Internet Web Application Hưng, Julian, Kevin Lim WAF rules, bot simulation &amp; blocking, OWASP vulnerability defense. 16:15 – 17:00 Closing &amp; Open Discussion — Lessons learned, Q&amp;A, advanced technical discussion. KEY KNOWLEDGE GAINED 1. CloudFront — Content Delivery &amp; Edge Optimization Understanding CDN fundamentals &amp; differences between Edge Location, Regional Edge Cache, and Origin. Advanced routing + caching strategy to reduce latency and boost global distribution speed. Implementing edge-level security layers (Origin Shield, cache policies, geo restrictions). → CloudFront is not only a CDN — it is also a performance + security perimeter for backend systems.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/event_4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>