<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Week 10: Exploring AWS AI/ML Foundations and Modern Generative AI Architectures :: AWS Intership Report</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_10/index.html</link>
    <description>Objectives: Understand the core components of AWS’s AI/ML ecosystem and its end-to-end workflow. Learn how SageMaker supports data preparation, training, tuning, deployment, and MLOps integration. Study foundational models (FMs), prompt engineering techniques, and Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). Strengthen architectural thinking for scalable, secure, and efficient ML solutions on AWS. Tasks Completed: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Reviewed the overall AI/ML landscape and how AWS services support each stage of the ML lifecycle. - Studied best practices for preparing and labeling datasets for ML workflows. 10/11/2025 10/11/2025 AWS Docs, Internet, internal materials Tue - Learned key concepts of Amazon SageMaker: training jobs, tuning, deployment endpoints, and built-in MLOps features. - Explored Studio interface and environment setup for ML experimentation. 11/11/2025 11/11/2025 AWS ML Docs, SageMaker Guides Wed - Studied Generative AI with Amazon Bedrock: Bedrock architecture, Foundation Models (Claude, Llama, Titan), model selection criteria, and cost considerations. - Practiced prompt engineering patterns such as chain-of-thought and few-shot prompting. 12/11/2025 12/11/2025 AWS GenAI Docs, Internet Thu - Explored Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG): vector stores, knowledge bases, embedding generation, and orchestration workflows. - Learned how Bedrock Agents execute multi-step workflows and integrate external tools. 13/11/2025 13/11/2025 AWS Docs, mentor guidance Fri - Studied safety systems in generative AI: guardrails, content filtering, and responsible AI patterns. - Documented architectural insights into the Report Site, including ML workflow breakdown and optimized inference design. 14/11/2025 14/11/2025 AWS Docs, Internet, internal resources Results: Gained a solid foundation in AWS’s AI/ML ecosystem, from data preparation to deployment. Understood modern generative AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock and relevant Foundation Models. Learned prompt engineering techniques and RAG architectures for building intelligent applications. Strengthened architectural awareness for scalable, cost-effective ML deployments.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>