<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Event 1 :: AWS Intership Report</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/event_1/index.html</link>
    <description>EVENT REPORT: AWS Cloud Day Vietnam 2025 &amp; GenAI Track Date: Thursday, September 18, 2025&#xA;Time: 9:00 AM – 5:00 PM&#xA;Location: AWS Vietnam Office, Bitexco Financial Tower, District 1, Ho Chi Minh City&#xA;Event Objectives Introduce the latest industry trends from AWS, with a strong focus on Generative AI. Present enterprise case studies from major organizations in Vietnam and the region. Discuss leadership strategy and organizational management in the AI era. Explore best practices for security, AI adoption, and real-world AI agent applications. Speakers Morning Sessions Hon. Government Speaker — Opening remarks. Eric Yeo — Country General Manager, Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos &amp; Myanmar, AWS. Dr. Jens Lottner — CEO, Techcombank. Ms. Trang Phung — CEO &amp; Co-Founder, U2U Network. Jaime Valles — Vice President, General Manager APJ, AWS. Jeff Johnson — Managing Director, ASEAN, AWS (Moderator). Panelists Vu Van — Co-founder &amp; CEO, ELSA Corp. Nguyen Hoa Binh — Chairman, Nexttech Group. Dieter Botha — CEO, TymeX. Afternoon Sessions Kien Nguyen — Solutions Architect, AWS. Michael Armentano — Principal WW GTM Specialist, AWS. Jun Kai Loke — AI/ML Specialist SA, AWS. Tamelly Lim — Storage Specialist SA, AWS. Binh Tran — Senior Solutions Architect, AWS. Taiki Dang — Solutions Architect, AWS. Session Highlights Part 1 — Main Sessions (AWS Cloud Day Vietnam) Opening &amp; Keynote (Eric Yeo, AWS):&#xA;Vision of AWS in Vietnam and the broader Southeast Asia region.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/event_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>