<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1. Worklog :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/index.html</link><description>Week 1: Làm quen với AWS Control Console và các dịch vụ AWS cơ bản</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 1: Introduction to AWS and Basic AWS Services</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_1/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_1/index.html</guid><description>Week 1 Goals: Get familiar with the First Cloud Journey (FCJ) environment. Understand Networking concepts related to AWS services Understand basic AWS services — what they are and how they work. Tasks completed this week: Day Task Start Date Completion Date Reference Material Mon - Get familiar with the FCJ working environment. - Read and note the rules and regulations at the internship unit. 08/09/2025 08/09/2025 https://policies.fcjuni.com/ Tue - Learn networking technologies and concepts: + NIC (Network Interface Card) + DNS (Domain Name System) + IP Addresses + CDN (Content Delivery Network) 09/09/2025 09/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Wed - Work at the office - Continue learning networking technologies and concepts: + IPv4/6 + NAT (Network Address Translator) + CIDR (Classless Inter-Domain Routing) + DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) + VPN (Virtual Private Network) + ENI (Elastic Network Interface) + Internet Gateway (AWS) 10/09/2025 10/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Thu - Learn AWS services: + IAM + EC2 (Elastic Compute Cloud) + VPC (Virtual Private Cloud) + VPC peering + Transit Gateway + NAT Gateway + Route table 11/09/2025 11/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Fri - Practice: + Create an AWS root account + Launch an EC2 instance + Learn about EC2 Access Keys, their purpose, and how to use them 12/09/2025 12/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Week 1 Results: Understood what AWS is and how its basic services are used. Gained general knowledge about networking technologies and concepts to better understand how AWS services operate. Successfully created and configured an AWS Free Tier root account. Got familiar with the AWS Management Console and learned how to find, access, and use services from the web interface. Modules watched Week 1: Module 01-01 - Điện Toán Đám Mây Là Gì ? Module 01-02 - Điều Gì Tạo Nên Sự Khác Biệt Của AWS ? Module 01-03 - Bắt Đầu Hành Trình Lên Mây Như Thế Nào Module 01-04 - Hạ Tầng Toàn Cầu Của AWS Module 01-05 - Công Cụ Quản Lý AWS Services Module 01-06 - Tối Ưu Hóa Chi Phí Trên AWS và Làm Việc Với AWS Support Module 01-07 - Thực Hành và Nghiên Cứu Bổ Sung Module 02-01 - AWS Virtual Private Cloud Module 02-02 - VPC Security and Multi-VPC features Module 02-03 - VPN - DirectConnect - LoadBalancer - ExtraResources</description></item><item><title>Week 2: Exploring AWS Compute and Storage Services. Getting familiar with HUGO and related development tools</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_2/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_2/index.html</guid><description>Week 2 Objectives: Understand the key compute and storage services on AWS. Get familiar with development and deployment tools (HUGO, PowerShell). Learn the basics of containerization and its usage on AWS (ECS, EKS, Docker). Attend an AWS-hosted event to expand knowledge and community connection. Tasks Completed This Week: Day Task Start Date End Date Reference Source Mon - Reviewed EC2 concepts from Week 1: Instance Types, AMI, Key Pair, Elastic Block Store. - Continued with extended topics on Auto Scaling, EFS/FSx, and Lightsail. 15/09/2025 15/09/2025 Internet &amp; Mentor-provided materials Tue - Studied AWS storage services: + Amazon S3 (Simple Storage Service) + S3 Bucket structure, Access Point, Storage Class + Static Website Hosting and CORS configuration + Glacier and cold storage classes - Learned about SSL/TLS, data encryption, and secure data transmission. 16/09/2025 16/09/2025 Internet &amp; Mentor-provided materials Wed - Installed and learned to use HUGO for building static websites. - Installed and practiced with PowerShell for Windows environment operations. 17/09/2025 17/09/2025 Internet &amp; HUGO Documentation Thu - Attended the Vietnam Cloud Day 2025 event hosted by AWS. - Took notes on key topics, trends, and AWS’s strategy in Vietnam. 18/09/2025 18/09/2025 AWS Vietnam Cloud Day 2025 Event Fri - Learned about containerization concepts: + Docker, Kubernetes + AWS ECS (Elastic Container Service) and EKS (Elastic Kubernetes Service). - Understood how AWS deploys and manages containers in production environments. 19/09/2025 19/09/2025 Internet &amp; Mentor-provided materials Results Achieved in Week 2: Strengthened understanding of EC2, Auto Scaling, and extended compute services. Gained in-depth knowledge of Amazon S3 — storage management, access control, and data classes. Successfully installed and used HUGO and PowerShell for development workflows. Participated in AWS Vietnam Cloud Day 2025, gaining insights into AWS strategies and trends. Learned the fundamentals of containerization and how AWS applies it through ECS/EKS. Modules Completed in Week 2: Module 03-01 - Compute VM on AWS Module 03-02 - EC2 Autoscaling - EFS/FSx - Lightsail - MGN Module 04-01 - Storage Services on AWS Module 04-02 - Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3) - Access Point - Storage Class Module 04-03 - S3 Static Website &amp; CORS - Control Access - Object Key &amp; Performance - Glacier</description></item><item><title>Week 3: Setting up the report site with Hugo, exploring AWS security and database services</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_3/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_3/index.html</guid><description>Week 3 Objectives: Set up and deploy the internship report site using Hugo and GitHub Pages. Reinforce understanding of previous modules (Compute, VPC, Storage). Learn about IAM Policies, JWT Authentication, and AWS Database Services (RDS, DynamoDB). Research Monitoring and Cost Optimization topics for upcoming weeks. Tasks Completed This Week: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Set up and configure the report site using Hugo and GitHub Pages. - Learned about static site structure, Hugo directory hierarchy, and Markdown content management. - Studied GitHub Actions for automating the build and deploy process. 22/09/2025 22/09/2025 Internet and Hugo Docs Tue - Completed Module 04-04: Snow Family – Storage Gateway – Backup. - Studied Access Keys, AWS KMS, EBS Snapshots, and DynamoDB. - Practiced configuring Storage Gateway to understand on-premises and cloud synchronization. 23/09/2025 23/09/2025 Internet and mentor-provided resources Wed - Reviewed Modules 01–04 (Compute, VPC, Storage). - Researched AWS IAM Policies and secure access configuration. - Experimented with assigning IAM permissions for Hugo deployment via GitHub Pages. 24/09/2025 24/09/2025 Internet and AWS IAM Documentation Thu - Learned about JWT (JSON Web Token) and its role in user authentication. - Studied setup processes for RDS and DynamoDB. - Built a small demo API using JWT Authentication and DynamoDB for data storage. 25/09/2025 25/09/2025 Internet and mentor-provided resources Fri - Summarized weekly learning progress for mid-term reporting. - Reviewed Hugo site structure and updated weekly sections. - Studied AWS Monitoring and Cost Optimization best practices to prepare for the next week. 26/09/2025 26/09/2025 Internet and AWS official documentation Results Achieved in Week 3: Successfully set up and deployed the internship report site using Hugo and GitHub Pages. Reinforced foundational understanding of Compute, VPC, Storage, and IAM concepts. Gained hands-on experience with JWT authentication and DynamoDB integration. Developed awareness of AWS monitoring and cost management practices. Modules Completed in Week 3: Module 04-04 - Snow Family - Storage Gateway - Backup</description></item><item><title>Week 4: Security and Identity Management on AWS. Integrating CloudWatch and Cost Explorer into the project</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_4/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_4/index.html</guid><description>Weekly Objectives: Understand the Shared Responsibility Model and AWS identity management services. Learn the core security services: IAM, Cognito, KMS, Security Hub, and AWS Organization. Apply knowledge in practice by integrating CloudWatch and Cost Explorer into the reporting system. Get familiar with automation tools (GitHub Actions) and Python SDK (boto3) for interacting with AWS services. Tasks Completed This Week: Day Tasks Start Date End Date Resources Used Mon - Added cloudwatch.py to the project. - Learned how to use boto3 to call AWS services via Python. - Reviewed Python, Shell, and NodeJS basics to support system development. 29/09/2025 29/09/2025 Internet and mentor-provided resources Tue - Studied modules: + 05-01 - Shared Responsibility Model + 05-02 - AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) + 05-03 - Amazon Cognito - Deployed the report website using GitHub Actions. - Learned about Redis and caching mechanisms in applications. 30/09/2025 30/09/2025 Internet, AWS docs, mentor guidance Wed - Added costexplorer.py and s3.py to the project. - Explored advanced Python syntax and practices. - Studied how to query cost and storage data via AWS SDK. 01/10/2025 01/10/2025 Internet and mentor-provided resources Thu - Studied modules: + 05-04 - AWS Organization + 05-05 - AWS Identity Center + 05-06 - AWS Key Management Service (KMS) + 05-07 - AWS Security Hub + 05-08 - Hands-on &amp; Additional Research. 02/10/2025 02/10/2025 Internet, AWS SkillBuilder, mentor input Fri - Translated and edited 3 official AWS admin blogs. - Summarized main insights related to identity and cloud security. 03/10/2025 03/10/2025 AWS Blog and internal documentation Weekly Achievements: Gained in-depth understanding of the Shared Responsibility Model and AWS security best practices. Mastered IAM, Cognito, and KMS for managing identities and data encryption. Successfully integrated CloudWatch and Cost Explorer into the reporting project for automatic cost and performance tracking. Practiced automated deployment with GitHub Actions, improving basic CI/CD skills. Enhanced Python proficiency and learned to use boto3 for AWS service interaction. Improved ability to read and analyze AWS security documentation and real-world blog content. Modules Covered in Week 4: Module 05-01 - Shared Responsibility Model Module 05-02 - AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) Module 05-03 - Amazon Cognito Module 05-04 - AWS Organization Module 05-05 - AWS Identity Center Module 05-06 - AWS Key Management Service (KMS) Module 05-07 - AWS Security Hub Module 05-08 - Hands-on &amp; Additional Research</description></item><item><title>Week 5: Strengthening AWS Database Knowledge and Enhancing the Internship Report Site</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_5/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_5/index.html</guid><description>Weekly Objectives: Review fundamental database concepts and understand the operational model of RDS and Aurora. Explore advanced AWS database services such as Redshift and ElastiCache. Apply knowledge in practice through improvements to the internship report site (Report Site). Refine technical writing and presentation skills through blog adjustments and documentation editing. Tasks Completed This Week: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Learning Resources Mon - Worked at the office to revise and adjust 3 translated technical blogs as requested by admins. - Reviewed core database concepts, including OLTP/OLAP models and primary-replica architectures. 06/10/2025 06/10/2025 Internal documentation and Internet Tue - Studied Module 06-01 - Database Concepts Review and Module 06-02 - Amazon RDS &amp; Amazon Aurora. - Learned about backup, recovery, and auto-scaling mechanisms in RDS/Aurora. - Practiced deploying test databases through the AWS Console. 07/10/2025 07/10/2025 AWS Skill Builder, Internet Wed - Studied Module 06-03 - Amazon Redshift and Amazon ElastiCache. - Worked at the office to enhance the Report Site interface using Hugo’s Relearn theme. - Learned about caching mechanisms and analytics in AWS. 08/10/2025 08/10/2025 Internet and HUGO Documentation Thu - Researched DynamoDB and compared relational vs. non-relational database models. - Studied AWS Key Management Service (KMS) to understand encryption mechanisms in database systems. 09/10/2025 09/10/2025 Internet and mentor-provided materials Fri - Consolidated knowledge of AWS database services (RDS, Aurora, Redshift, DynamoDB, ElastiCache). - Documented findings and insights for practical implementation. - Prepared for the next week’s topics on DevOps and CI/CD pipeline fundamentals. 10/10/2025 10/10/2025 Internet and mentor-provided materials Weekly Outcomes: Gained a clear understanding of relational vs. non-relational database models in AWS. Achieved proficiency in working with Amazon RDS, Aurora, Redshift, and ElastiCache. Improved and restyled the internship Report Site using the Hugo Relearn theme. Strengthened technical writing and documentation refinement skills. Extended learning: DynamoDB, KMS, Database Encryption Established a solid foundation for upcoming topics on DevOps and CI/CD automation. Modules Studied in Week 5: Module 06-01 - Database Concepts Review Module 06-02 - Amazon RDS &amp; Amazon Aurora Module 06-03 - Amazon Redshift - ElastiCache</description></item></channel></rss>