<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 7: Backend System Optimization and Expanding AWS Cost Monitoring Features :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_7/index.html</link><description>Objectives: Develop and extend key backend API routes (CloudWatch, Cost Explorer, S3, SecurityHub). Optimize asynchronous processing and enhance caching performance with Redis. Deepen understanding of Python’s runtime behavior, the GIL (Global Interpreter Lock), and parallel processing. Strengthen cost visibility and performance analysis through custom AWS monitoring APIs. Tasks Completed: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Worked at the office to add api/routes/cloudwatch.py for monitoring data collection. - Optimized log-handling functions and implemented caching for CloudWatch data using Redis. 20/10/2025 20/10/2025 AWS Docs, mentor guidance, Internet Tue - Added api/routes/costexplorer.py to aggregate and analyze AWS service costs. - Enhanced concurrent query execution and caching to reduce API response latency. 21/10/2025 21/10/2025 AWS Docs, Internet, mentor guidance Wed - Implemented api/routes/s3.py for S3 data access. - Studied IAM Policy control and cost optimization methods in S3 through data tiering (Storage Classes). 22/10/2025 22/10/2025 AWS Docs, Internet, mentor guidance Thu - Updated the Report Site content, adding a new “Cloud Optimization” section to document cost management practices. - Authored internal guide on configuring caching and async tasks in the project. 23/10/2025 23/10/2025 Internet, mentor-provided materials Fri - Added api/routes/securityhub.py for security alert aggregation. - Researched Python’s internal behavior: GIL, async, and parallel execution. - Improved Redis/FastAPI workflow integration and efficiency in backend operations. 24/10/2025 24/10/2025 Internet, internal documentation Results: Completed development of key backend API routes: CloudWatch, Cost Explorer, S3, and SecurityHub. Significantly improved backend performance through caching and asynchronous processing. Gained deeper insight into Python’s internal mechanisms and optimized FastAPI’s concurrency handling. Initiated Cloud Optimization implementation in the project — focusing on cost monitoring and performance tuning. Strengthened backend engineering, resource management, and system efficiency skills.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>