<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Access S3 from VPC :: AWS Intership Report</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/3-s3-vpc/index.html</link>
    <description>Using Gateway endpoint In this section, you will create a Gateway eendpoint to access Amazon S3 from an EC2 instance. The Gateway endpoint will allow upload an object to S3 buckets without using the Public Internet. To create an endpoint, you must specify the VPC in which you want to create the endpoint, and the service (in this case, S3) to which you want to establish the connection.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/3-s3-vpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create a gateway endpoint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/3-s3-vpc/3.1-create-gwe/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/3-s3-vpc/3.1-create-gwe/index.html</guid>
      <description>Open the Amazon VPC console In the navigation pane, choose Endpoints, then click Create Endpoint: Note&#xD;You will see 6 existing VPC endpoints that support AWS Systems Manager (SSM). These endpoints were deployed automatically by the CloudFormation Templates for this workshop.&#xA;In the Create endpoint console: Specify name of the endpoint: s3-gwe In service category, choose AWS services</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test the Gateway Endpoint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/3-s3-vpc/3.2-test-gwe/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/3-s3-vpc/3.2-test-gwe/index.html</guid>
      <description>Create S3 bucket Navigate to S3 management console In the Bucket console, choose Create bucket In the Create bucket console Name the bucket: choose a name that hasn’t been given to any bucket globally (hint: lab number and your name) Leave other fields as they are (default) Scroll down and choose Create bucket</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>