<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Access S3 from on-premises :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/index.html</link><description>Overview In this section, you will create an Interface endpoint to access Amazon S3 from a simulated on-premises environment. The Interface endpoint will allow you to route to Amazon S3 over a VPN connection from your simulated on-premises environment.
Why using Interface endpoint:
Gateway endpoints only work with resources running in the VPC where they are created. Interface endpoints work with resources running in VPC, and also resources running in on-premises environments. Connectivty from your on-premises environment to the cloud can be provided by AWS Site-to-Site VPN or AWS Direct Connect. Interface endpoints allow you to connect to services powered by AWS PrivateLink. These services include some AWS services, services hosted by other AWS customers and partners in their own VPCs (referred to as PrivateLink Endpoint Services), and supported AWS Marketplace Partner services. For this workshop, we will focus on connecting to Amazon S3.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prepare the environment</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-1.-prepare/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-1.-prepare/index.html</guid><description>To prepare for this part of the workshop you will need to:
Deploying a CloudFormation stack Modifying a VPC route table. These components work together to simulate on-premises DNS forwarding and name resolution.
Deploy the CloudFormation stack The CloudFormation template will create additional services to support an on-premises simulation:
One Route 53 Private Hosted Zone that hosts Alias records for the PrivateLink S3 endpoint One Route 53 Inbound Resolver endpoint that enables “VPC Cloud” to resolve inbound DNS resolution requests to the Private Hosted Zone One Route 53 Outbound Resolver endpoint that enables “VPC On-prem” to forward DNS requests for S3 to “VPC Cloud”</description></item><item><title>Create an S3 Interface endpoint</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-2.-create-interface-endpoint/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-2.-create-interface-endpoint/index.html</guid><description>In this section you will create and test an S3 interface endpoint using the simulated on-premises environment deployed as part of this workshop.
Return to the Amazon VPC menu. In the navigation pane, choose Endpoints, then click Create Endpoint.
In Create endpoint console:
Name the interface endpoint In Service category, choose aws services In the Search box, type S3 and press Enter. Select the endpoint named com.amazonaws.us-east-1.s3. Ensure that the Type column indicates Interface.</description></item><item><title>Test the Interface Endpoint</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-3.-test-endpoint/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-3.-test-endpoint/index.html</guid><description>Get the regional DNS name of S3 interface endpoint From the Amazon VPC menu, choose Endpoints.
Click the name of newly created endpoint: s3-interface-endpoint. Click details and save the regional DNS name of the endpoint (the first one) to your text-editor for later use.
Connect to EC2 instance in “VPC On-prem” Navigate to Session manager by typing “session manager” in the search box</description></item><item><title>On-premises DNS Simulation</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-4.-dns-simulation/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/workshop/4.-s3---onprem/4-4.-dns-simulation/index.html</guid><description>AWS PrivateLink endpoints have a fixed IP address in each Availability Zone where they are deployed, for the life of the endpoint (until it is deleted). These IP addresses are attached to Elastic Network Interfaces (ENIs). AWS recommends using DNS to resolve the IP addresses for endpoints so that downstream applications use the latest IP addresses when ENIs are added to new AZs, or deleted over time.
In this section, you will create a forwarding rule to send DNS resolution requests from a simulated on-premises environment to a Route 53 Private Hosted Zone. This section leverages the infrastructure deployed by CloudFormation in the Prepare the environment section.</description></item></channel></rss>