<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 9: Deepening Cloud Optimization Skills and Exploring Web Application Performance &amp; Security :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_9/index.html</link><description>Objectives: Strengthen cloud optimization knowledge across performance, cost management, and scaling. Explore web application security fundamentals and threat mitigation patterns. Practice hands-on AWS labs to reinforce concepts learned in previous weeks. Improve understanding of CDN behavior, caching strategy, and edge security controls. Tasks Completed: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Continued reviewing AWS architectural best practices with focus on performance optimization. - Added new technical explanations to the Report Site regarding compute and storage efficiency. 03/11/2025 03/11/2025 Internet, AWS Docs, mentor guidance Tue - Completed hands-on labs covering EC2 resizing, load balancing, and horizontal scaling strategies. - Practiced cost-awareness techniques such as rightsizing and choosing efficient instance families. 04/11/2025 04/11/2025 AWS Labs, internal documentation Wed - Studied CDN acceleration concepts: request routing, caching invalidation, and edge optimization. - Reviewed how CloudFront integrates with origin servers for performance and security. 05/11/2025 05/11/2025 AWS Edge Services Docs Thu - Learned core web application protection strategies: mitigating OWASP Top 10 risks, rate limiting, and bot defense patterns. - Studied how AWS WAF rulesets protect applications at scale. 06/11/2025 06/11/2025 AWS Security Docs, Internet Fri - Reinforced the week’s learning with lab-style exercises: configuring WAF rules, testing caching impacts, and analyzing request flow through CloudFront. - Documented findings for future optimization work. 07/11/2025 07/11/2025 Internet, mentor-provided materials Results: Strengthened understanding of AWS performance optimization techniques across compute, storage, and networking. Improved familiarity with CDN behavior, caching, edge optimization, and request flow. Gained practical security knowledge: threat mitigation, OWASP Top 10 patterns, and WAF-based protection. Reinforced learning through hands-on labs. Progressed steadily toward more advanced optimization and security architecture work.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>