<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>5. Workshop :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/index.html</link><description>This is our group Workshop. Please review the below contents. Content Overview Prerequisites Create VPC &amp; Subnets Create Internet Gateway Create NAT Gateway Configure Route Tables Launch EC2 Instances Connectivity Tests Cleanup</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Overview</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/1-overview/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/1-overview/index.html</guid><description>Build a Basic AWS VPC with Public &amp; Private Subnets In this workshop, you will build a simple network foundation in AWS using Amazon VPC (Virtual Private Cloud). The goal is to help beginners understand how networking works in the cloud, and how different components connect together to form a secure, controlled environment.
You will create a VPC with two subnets:
A Public Subnet – allows resources (like EC2 instances) to access the Internet directly. A Private Subnet – isolated from the public Internet by default for better security. To enable the private subnet to download packages and access online services without being exposed publicly, you will configure:</description></item><item><title>2. Prerequisites</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/2-prerequisites/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/2-prerequisites/index.html</guid><description>Before starting the workshop, ensure you have access to the following:
Accounts &amp; Access An AWS Account IAM User with permissions to: Amazon VPC Amazon EC2 Elastic IP NAT Gateway Internet Gateway Recommended policy: AdministratorAccess (for lab purposes only) If you are using an IAM user, make sure you have access keys or console login credentials.
Cost Notice This workshop includes creating a NAT Gateway, which is a billable resource. To minimize cost, you should delete all created resources during the cleanup step.</description></item><item><title>3. Create VPC &amp; Subnets</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/3-vpc-subnets/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/3-vpc-subnets/index.html</guid><description>In this component, you will create your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) and define two subnets:
1 Public Subnet (Internet accessible) 1 Private Subnet (no direct Internet access) 3.1 Create the VPC Open AWS Management Console Navigate to Services → VPC Click Create VPC Select VPC Only Enter the details: Name tag: Workshop-VPC IPv4 CIDR: 10.0.0.0/16 Keep all other settings at default Click Create VPC</description></item><item><title>4. Create Internet Gateway</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/4-ig/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/4-ig/index.html</guid><description>The Internet Gateway (IGW) allows resources inside your Public Subnet to send and receive traffic from the Internet. Without it, even a subnet with public IP will still be isolated.
4.1 Create an Internet Gateway In the AWS Console, open VPC service On the left panel, select Internet Gateways Click Create internet gateway Fill in: Name tag: Workshop-IGW Click Create internet gateway</description></item><item><title>5. Create NAT Gateway</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/5-nat/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/5-nat/index.html</guid><description>The NAT Gateway allows instances in the Private Subnet to access the Internet without being publicly exposed. This is how the private EC2 will yum install, download updates, etc.
5.1 Allocate Elastic IP In the left VPC menu, select Elastic IPs Click Allocate Elastic IP address Choose default settings Click Allocate 5.2 Create NAT Gateway In the left VPC panel, go to NAT gateways Click Create NAT gateway Configure: Field Value Name Workshop-NAT Availability mode Zonal Subnet Public-Subnet Connectivity type Public Elastic IP allocation Select the one you just created Click Create NAT gateway</description></item><item><title>6. Configure Route Tables</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/6-routetb/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/6-routetb/index.html</guid><description>Route Tables decide how traffic flows inside your VPC.
In this component, you will:
Create separate route tables for public and private subnets Route Internet traffic from the public subnet → Internet Gateway Route private subnet traffic → NAT Gateway for outbound access 6.1 Create Route Table for Public Subnet In VPC console, open Route Tables Click Create route table Enter: Name: Public-RT VPC: Workshop-VPC Click Create route table</description></item><item><title>7. Launch EC2 Instances</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/7-ec2/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/7-ec2/index.html</guid><description>You will now deploy two EC2 instances:
Instance Subnet Access EC2-Public Public-Subnet SSH directly from Internet EC2-Private Private-Subnet No public IP — accessible only through Public EC2 Both will use the same AMI and instance type for simplicity.
7.1 Create a Key Pair Go to EC2 Console Left panel → Key Pairs Click Create key pair Set: Name: Workshop-Key Type: RSA Format: .pem (Linux/Mac) or .ppk (Windows PuTTY) Download and store securely</description></item><item><title>8. Connectivity Tests</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/8-connectivity-tests/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/8-connectivity-tests/index.html</guid><description>Now that both EC2 instances are running, it’s time to validate network behavior and confirm the VPC is functioning correctly.
This component verifies three things:
Public EC2 is reachable from your local machine Private EC2 is only reachable from the Public EC2 (not directly from the internet) Private EC2 can access the internet through the NAT Gateway 8.1 Connect to the Public EC2 Instance Open the EC2 Console → Instances Copy the Public IPv4 of EC2-Public SSH into the instance This step is dependent on what type of machine you’re using and can vary among different tools. We are using Powershell on a Windows 11 OS PC for this Workshop. You can use other alternatives if you prefer.</description></item><item><title>9. Clean Up</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/9-cleanup/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/5-workshop/9-cleanup/index.html</guid><description>To avoid unnecessary charges — especially from the NAT Gateway — you should remove all created resources after finishing the workshop.
Follow the steps below in order:
9.1 Terminate EC2 Instances Open EC2 Console Select both EC2-Public and EC2-Private Click Instance state → Terminate (This process may take some time) Confirm termination 9.2 Delete NAT Gateway Go to VPC Console → NAT Gateways Select Workshop-NAT Click Actions → Delete NAT Gateway (This process may take some time) Confirm the action Wait until NAT Gateway shows as Deleted before moving on.</description></item></channel></rss>