<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 6: Enhancing Multilingual Report Site and Exploring Basic DevOps Practices on AWS :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_6/index.html</link><description>Objectives: Extend and improve the Report Site with multilingual (i18n) support. Review and reinforce core AWS concepts from previous weeks (Database, IAM, KMS). Get familiar with basic DevOps workflows on AWS, including CI/CD automation and infrastructure management. Study monitoring, logging, and cost optimization services in AWS. Tasks Completed: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Worked at the office. - Implement multilingual support for the Report Site. 13/10/2025 13/10/2025 HUGO Docs and GitHub Pages Documentation Tue - Reviewed core DevOps concepts: CI/CD pipeline, GitHub Actions, staging and production environments. - Optimized workflow YAML configurations from previous deployments for improved automation. 14/10/2025 14/10/2025 Internet and official docs Wed - Updated and tested the Report Site UI after adding multilingual support. - Wrote an internal guideline for configuring the Relearn theme and translating site content. - Studied AWS CloudFormation and CodePipeline for DevOps infrastructure automation. 15/10/2025 15/10/2025 Internet and AWS Documentation Thu - Studied AWS Monitoring and Logging tools: CloudWatch, CloudTrail, and AWS Config. - Learned the basics of Infrastructure as Code (IaC) and how it can be applied in AWS deployments. 16/10/2025 16/10/2025 Internet and AWS Documentation Fri - Consolidated weekly progress and prepared for the upcoming DevOps practical phase. - Updated and refined bilingual content across previous report weeks. 17/10/2025 17/10/2025 Internet and official docs Results: Successfully implemented multilingual functionality for the report site. Gained hands-on understanding of the DevOps workflow using GitHub Actions and CI/CD pipelines. Strengthened foundational knowledge of AWS monitoring and automation tools (CloudWatch, CloudTrail, AWS Config). Improved technical documentation structure and content organization within Hugo. Reviewed content from IAM, Database, and Cloud Monitoring modules.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>