<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Week 3: Setting up the report site with Hugo, exploring AWS security and database services :: AWS Intership Report</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_3/index.html</link>
    <description>Week 3 Objectives: Set up and deploy the internship report site using Hugo and GitHub Pages. Reinforce understanding of previous modules (Compute, VPC, Storage). Learn about IAM Policies, JWT Authentication, and AWS Database Services (RDS, DynamoDB). Research Monitoring and Cost Optimization topics for upcoming weeks. Tasks Completed This Week: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Set up and configure the report site using Hugo and GitHub Pages. - Learned about static site structure, Hugo directory hierarchy, and Markdown content management. - Studied GitHub Actions for automating the build and deploy process. 22/09/2025 22/09/2025 Internet and Hugo Docs Tue - Completed Module 04-04: Snow Family – Storage Gateway – Backup. - Studied Access Keys, AWS KMS, EBS Snapshots, and DynamoDB. - Practiced configuring Storage Gateway to understand on-premises and cloud synchronization. 23/09/2025 23/09/2025 Internet and mentor-provided resources Wed - Reviewed Modules 01–04 (Compute, VPC, Storage). - Researched AWS IAM Policies and secure access configuration. - Experimented with assigning IAM permissions for Hugo deployment via GitHub Pages. 24/09/2025 24/09/2025 Internet and AWS IAM Documentation Thu - Learned about JWT (JSON Web Token) and its role in user authentication. - Studied setup processes for RDS and DynamoDB. - Built a small demo API using JWT Authentication and DynamoDB for data storage. 25/09/2025 25/09/2025 Internet and mentor-provided resources Fri - Summarized weekly learning progress for mid-term reporting. - Reviewed Hugo site structure and updated weekly sections. - Studied AWS Monitoring and Cost Optimization best practices to prepare for the next week. 26/09/2025 26/09/2025 Internet and AWS official documentation Results Achieved in Week 3: Successfully set up and deployed the internship report site using Hugo and GitHub Pages. Reinforced foundational understanding of Compute, VPC, Storage, and IAM concepts. Gained hands-on experience with JWT authentication and DynamoDB integration. Developed awareness of AWS monitoring and cost management practices. Modules Completed in Week 3: Module 04-04 - Snow Family - Storage Gateway - Backup</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>