<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 1: Introduction to AWS and Basic AWS Services :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_1/index.html</link><description>Objectives: Get familiar with the First Cloud Journey (FCJ) environment. Understand Networking concepts related to AWS services Understand basic AWS services — what they are and how they work. Tasks Completed: Day Task Start Date Completion Date Reference Material Mon - Get familiar with the FCJ working environment. - Read and note the rules and regulations at the internship unit. 08/09/2025 08/09/2025 https://policies.fcjuni.com/ Tue - Learn networking technologies and concepts: + NIC (Network Interface Card) + DNS (Domain Name System) + IP Addresses + CDN (Content Delivery Network) 09/09/2025 09/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Wed - Work at the office - Continue learning networking technologies and concepts: + IPv4/6 + NAT (Network Address Translator) + CIDR (Classless Inter-Domain Routing) + DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) + VPN (Virtual Private Network) + ENI (Elastic Network Interface) + Internet Gateway (AWS) 10/09/2025 10/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Thu - Learn AWS services: + IAM + EC2 (Elastic Compute Cloud) + VPC (Virtual Private Cloud) + VPC peering + Transit Gateway + NAT Gateway + Route table 11/09/2025 11/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Fri - Practice: + Create an AWS root account + Launch an EC2 instance + Learn about EC2 Access Keys, their purpose, and how to use them 12/09/2025 12/09/2025 Internet and materials provided by mentors Results: Understood what AWS is and how its basic services are used. Gained general knowledge about networking technologies and concepts to better understand how AWS services operate. Successfully created and configured an AWS Free Tier root account. Got familiar with the AWS Management Console and learned how to find, access, and use services from the web interface. Modules Learned: Module 01-01 - Điện Toán Đám Mây Là Gì ? Module 01-02 - Điều Gì Tạo Nên Sự Khác Biệt Của AWS ? Module 01-03 - Bắt Đầu Hành Trình Lên Mây Như Thế Nào Module 01-04 - Hạ Tầng Toàn Cầu Của AWS Module 01-05 - Công Cụ Quản Lý AWS Services Module 01-06 - Tối Ưu Hóa Chi Phí Trên AWS và Làm Việc Với AWS Support Module 01-07 - Thực Hành và Nghiên Cứu Bổ Sung Module 02-01 - AWS Virtual Private Cloud Module 02-02 - VPC Security and Multi-VPC features Module 02-03 - VPN - DirectConnect - LoadBalancer - ExtraResources</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>