<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 12: Strengthening AWS Security Architecture and Mastering Cloud Protection Best Practices :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_12/index.html</link><description>Objectives: Deepen understanding of AWS Security Pillars and modern cloud security strategies. Learn identity governance, detection mechanisms, infrastructure protection, and data security on AWS. Strengthen practical skills in securing workloads using IAM, KMS, logging systems, and network segmentation. Consolidate all security-related knowledge into final documentation for the Report Site. Tasks Completed: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Reference Sources Mon - Studied AWS Security Pillar concepts: Least Privilege, Zero Trust, and Defense in Depth. - Reviewed the Shared Responsibility Model and how to apply it across cloud workloads. 24/11/2025 24/11/2025 AWS Docs, Internet Tue - Learned Identity &amp; Access Management best practices: IAM roles, policies, credential rotation, MFA, and access validation. - Explored IAM Identity Center for centralized access management and permission boundaries for multi-account structures. 25/11/2025 25/11/2025 AWS Docs, security guides Wed - Researched Detection &amp; Monitoring services: CloudTrail, GuardDuty, Security Hub. - Studied logging patterns across layers (VPC Flow Logs, ALB logs, S3 access logs) and how to route alerts through EventBridge. 26/11/2025 26/11/2025 AWS Security Docs Thu - Focused on Infrastructure Protection: VPC segmentation, private/public subnet design, security groups vs NACLs, WAF integration, and Shield protections. - Reviewed workload protection basics for EC2 and containerized environments. 27/11/2025 27/11/2025 Internet, AWS Docs Fri - Studied Data Protection: encryption at-rest/in-transit, KMS key policies, key rotation, Secrets Manager, and Parameter Store usage patterns. - Reviewed common Incident Response playbooks: compromised credentials, S3 public exposure, malware detection, isolation steps, and automated response via Lambda. 28/11/2025 28/11/2025 AWS IR Docs, security blogs Results: Gained a full understanding of AWS Security Pillar concepts and how to enforce Least Privilege and Zero Trust. Strengthened identity and access governance skills across multi-account structures. Achieved solid command of detection systems (CloudTrail, GuardDuty, Security Hub) and logging architectures. Understood end-to-end infrastructure protection patterns including segmentation, WAF, Shield, SG/NACL design. Mastered data security fundamentals with KMS, encryption, and secrets management.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/1-worklog/week_12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>