<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event 3 :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/event_3/index.html</link><description>EVENT REPORT: Agentic Workflows &amp; AWS Bedrock Agent Deep Dive Event Objective:
Provide practical and advanced understanding of building automated workflows (Agentic Workflows) with AWS Bedrock Agent, along with optimization solutions introduced by CloudThinker.
AGENDA SUMMARY Time Topic Speaker Key Highlights 9:00 – 9:10 Opening Remarks Nguyen Gia Hung – Head of Solutions Architect Event objectives, context setting. 9:10 – 9:40 AWS Bedrock Agent Core Kien Nguyen – Solutions Architect Architecture breakdown, core features, execution model. 9:40 – 10:00 Use Case — Building Agentic Workflow on AWS Viet Pham – Founder &amp; CEO Real-world implementation example of automated agent workflows. 10:00 – 10:10 Introduction to CloudThinker Thang Ton – Co-founder &amp; COO Overview of the company and GenAI optimization approach. 10:10 – 10:40 CloudThinker Agentic Orchestration &amp; Context Optimization (L300) Henry Bui – Head of Engineering Deep dive into orchestration and context efficiency strategies. 10:40 – 11:00 Break &amp; Networking Relax and connect with speakers and participants. 11:00 – 12:00 CloudThinker Hack — Hands-on Workshop Kha Van Practical agent-building session using Bedrock. 12:00 Lunch &amp; Networking KEY TECHNICAL INSIGHTS 1. Core Architecture of AWS Bedrock Agent The presentation by Kien Nguyen clarified how Bedrock Agent automates multi-step and complex tasks by connecting Foundation Models (FMs) with internal systems and APIs. Execution Mechanism:
Agents use FM reasoning to understand user intent, break tasks into steps, and execute via Tools / Action Groups. Primary Benefits: Reduces custom code for multi-step workflows. Supports safety guardrails for secure internal system access. 2. Real Use Case — Agentic Workflow Construction Viet Pham’s demo demonstrated how sequential workflows can be transformed into fully automated agent-driven pipelines. Key takeaway: clearly defined capabilities and APIs are required for the agent to act accurately and reliably. 3. Workflow Optimization with CloudThinker CloudThinker focused on solving deep technical challenges (L300) surrounding Agent operation:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/4-events/event_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>