<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 5: Strengthening AWS Database Knowledge and Enhancing the Internship Report Site :: AWS Intership Report</title><link>https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_5/index.html</link><description>Objectives: Review fundamental database concepts and understand the operational model of RDS and Aurora. Explore advanced AWS database services such as Redshift and ElastiCache. Apply knowledge in practice through improvements to the internship report site (Report Site). Refine technical writing and presentation skills through blog adjustments and documentation editing. Tasks Completed: Day Tasks Start Date Completion Date Learning Resources Mon - Worked at the office to revise and adjust 3 translated technical blogs as requested by admins. - Reviewed core database concepts, including OLTP/OLAP models and primary-replica architectures. 06/10/2025 06/10/2025 Internal documentation and Internet Tue - Studied Module 06-01 - Database Concepts Review and Module 06-02 - Amazon RDS &amp; Amazon Aurora. - Learned about backup, recovery, and auto-scaling mechanisms in RDS/Aurora. - Practiced deploying test databases through the AWS Console. 07/10/2025 07/10/2025 AWS Skill Builder, Internet Wed - Studied Module 06-03 - Amazon Redshift and Amazon ElastiCache. - Worked at the office to enhance the Report Site interface using Hugo’s Relearn theme. - Learned about caching mechanisms and analytics in AWS. 08/10/2025 08/10/2025 Internet and HUGO Documentation Thu - Researched DynamoDB and compared relational vs. non-relational database models. - Studied AWS Key Management Service (KMS) to understand encryption mechanisms in database systems. 09/10/2025 09/10/2025 Internet and mentor-provided materials Fri - Consolidated knowledge of AWS database services (RDS, Aurora, Redshift, DynamoDB, ElastiCache). - Documented findings and insights for practical implementation. - Prepared for the next week’s topics on DevOps and CI/CD pipeline fundamentals. 10/10/2025 10/10/2025 Internet and mentor-provided materials Results: Gained a clear understanding of relational vs. non-relational database models in AWS. Achieved proficiency in working with Amazon RDS, Aurora, Redshift, and ElastiCache. Improved and restyled the internship Report Site using the Hugo Relearn theme. Strengthened technical writing and documentation refinement skills. Extended learning: DynamoDB, KMS, Database Encryption Established a solid foundation for upcoming topics on DevOps and CI/CD automation. Modules Learned: Module 06-01 - Database Concepts Review Module 06-02 - Amazon RDS &amp; Amazon Aurora Module 06-03 - Amazon Redshift - ElastiCache</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wwdinhww.github.io/FCJ-report-HUGO-SE192671/en/worklog/week_5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>